# Angshuman Mazumdar

I believe that engineering and art go hand-in-hand. I am also an ardent follower of interactive media, especially video games, because I believe that they provide a great platform for experiences to flourish, and ideas to be communicated through stories that leave a lasting impression in our minds.





angshuman.mazumdar@gmail.com



🖄 West Lafayette, Indiana



https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/

# (585) 406-9165

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/angshuman-mazumdar-a0b75a130/

(O) https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/portfolio

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Science (Computer Graphics Technology)

Purdue University, West Lafayette (Indiana) August 2019 – Expected May 2021 (GPA – 3.97)

#### **Capstone Project**

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester (New York) January 2019 – May 2019

#### **Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication)**

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore 2015 - 2019 (CGPA - 8.69)

#### **High School and Senior School**

Don Bosco Senior Secondary School, Guwahati 2003 - 2015 (93.4%)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

**Purdue University** 08/2020 - Present West Lafayette (IN, USA)

• Responsible for assisting students with learning NX 12.0, for the course "Graphical Communication and Spatial Analysis"

## Supporter

The Power of Connection (Documentary) 05/2020 - 12/2020 West Lafayette (IN, USA)

#### **Graphic Designer**

MOX - Movement of Expression 02/2018 - 08/2019 Shillong, India

## **Trainee**

Bharti Airtel 05/2018 - 06/2018 Chandigarh, India

• Summer internship. Helped in streamlining the pipeline for form data collection and organization through VBA in Microsoft Excel which reduced the time for data retrieval and organization

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Design Advisor for Team Vimaanas (01/2017 - 06/2018) Team Vimaanas is the official Micro-Class RC Aviation team of VIT.

## Design Head (BEAM-VIT) (06/2016 - 05/2017)

BEAM-VIT was a club of VIT University. Also held the position of Design Co-Chair for BIDSF 2017. BIDSF is an annual event organized by the Biotech Division of VIT.

#### **SOFTWARE FAMILIARITY**

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premiere Pro Adobe After Effects Unreal Engine 4 Unity3D World Machine Houdini Autodesk Maya Autodesk 3DS Max Blender Trimble SketchUp NX 12.0 C++ and C# HTML and CSS

# **MAJOR PROJECTS**

Walking in a Crowd Full of Virtual Characters: Effects of Virtual Character Appearance on Human Movement Behavior (09/2019 - 01/2020)

Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel)

- Paper on effects of a virtual crowd with varied appearance
- Focused on the relation between human movement in such virtual crowds
- Targeted towards future crowd-based studies and scenarios

# Embodiment for the Difference: A VR Experience of Bipolar **Disorder** (08/2019 – 12/2019)

- The objective was to develop a simulation in virtual reality to provide an experience of the effects of Bipolar Disorder; shed light on a few of the challenges a person suffering from bipolar disorder would have to face in their lives
- Platform used for delivering experience was Oculus Quest

# Parkinson's Disease Assist Device using Machine Learning and Internet of Things (07/2017 - 04/2018)

- Project focused on development of a prototype of a spoon which senses the hand motion of an individual suffering from Parkinson's disease.
- Basic idea was to provide counter motion to the trembling actions of a patient's hand, to minimize spills

# **LANGUAGES**

Native Language Assamese **English** Full working proficiency Hindi **Bilingual Proficiency** French Novice